<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Cirebon</string>
    <string name="wisatahari">Monday - Sunday</string>
    <string name="home1">Popular Places</string>
    <string name="riwayat">History</string>
    <string name="semua_kategori">All Categories</string>
    <string name="tempat_wisata">Tourism Site</string>
    <string name="belanja">Shop</string>
    <string name="wisata_kuliner">Food</string>
    <string name="fasilitas_publik">Public Facilities</string>
    <string name="trransportasi">Transportation</string>
    <string name="nama">Full Name</string>
    <string name="no_telepon">Phone</string>
    <string name="bahasa">Language</string>
    <string name="keluar">Log Out</string>
    <string name="tempat_wisata_popular">Popular Tourism Sites</string>
    <string name="tiket_keraton_kesepuhan">Entrance\t: Rp15.000 \nMuseum Pusaka\t\t: Rp 25.000 \nDalem Agung Pakungwati :\tRp 10.000</string>
    <string name="operasional_keraton_kesepuhan">Monday – Sunday (Everyday)  \n08.00 AM – 06:00 PM WIB</string>
    <string name="tiket_detail">Entrance Ticket</string>
    <string name="jam_detail">Operational Hours</string>
    <string name="lokasi_detail">Location</string>
    <string name="home_search">Search</string>
    <string name="detail_deskripsi">Description</string>
    <string name="deskripsi_keraton_kesepuhan">The beginning of the founding of Cirebon was founded by Kanjeng Prabu Siliwangi named Raden Wal directsang and he held the title of prince of Cakrabuana. The first palace that was established was the first palace of pakungwati which is now known as dung agung pakungwati located in the east. Then at that time Prince Cakrabuana as kuwu in Cirebon or the ruler whose territory only covered from around Losari Kulon to the direction of Juntih Indramayu also called mbah kuwu Cirebon or srimangana meaning small king. He was appointed by his own father was King Siliwangi. In 1479, the prince of Cakrabuana handed Cirebon to his nephew as well as his son-in-law Syeh Syarif Hidayatullah better known by his title Sunan Gunung Jati, which during the reign of Sunan Gunung Jati from 1479 developed and officially finally 1481 Cirebon declared itself an independent Islamic kingdom separated from Padjajaran. Originally Cirebon was under the Padjajaran region. Then Cirebon became the first Islamic kingdom in West Java and eventually developed into a fairly large kingdom because the territory according to the manuscript notes is not only West Java, Cirebon covers up to Singapore. Cirebon influence reaches Thailand. Cirebon is from the word caruban which means a mixed country because it consists of many ethnicities including Arabic, Sundanese, Javanese, Chinese, Madurese, Dayaks all because Cirebon is indeed an international port. Before the founding of Cirebon 1415 Admiral Cengko had come to Cirebon before going to Semarang to erect a lighthouse called the tower of fire which now only remains in ruins. At its peak Cirebon under the leadership of Sunan Gunung Jati ordered Fatahilah to expel the Portuguese in Sunda Kelapa and finally Fatahilah succeeded, then Fatahilah was appointed regent in the Sundanese coconut with the title of Prince of Jakarta and Cirebon in 1527 became a large kingdom called grage from the word Negeri gede.</string>
    <string name="maps_teks_detail">Click on Maps for detail</string>
    <string name="simpan_bahasa">Save</string>
    <string name="deskripsi_keraton_kanoman">The Kanoman Palace is one of the two buildings of the Cirebon sultanate, after the Kanoman palace was established in 1678 AD The Sultanate of Cirebon consisted of the Kasepuhan palace and the Kanoman palace. The greatness of Islam in western Java is inseparable from Cirebon. Sunan Gunung Jati is the person responsible for spreading Islam in West Java, so talking about Cirebon will not be separated from the figure of Syarif Hidayatullah or Sunan Gunung Jati. The Kanoman Palace was founded by Prince Mohamad Badridin or Prince Kertawijaya, who held the Sultan Anom I around 1678 AD Sunan Gunung Jati in the village of Astana, North Cirebon. Historical relics in the Kanoman Palace are closely related to the spread of the religion of Islam that is actively carried out by Sunan Gunung Jati, also known as Syarif Hidayatullah. Kanoman Palace Complex which has an area of ​​around 6 hectares is located behind the Kanoman market. In this Kraton lived the twelfth sultan named Raja Muhammad Emiruddin with his family. Kanoman Palace is a vast complex, consisting of ancient buildings. one of them is a hut named witana ward which is the forerunner of the Palace which is almost five times the football field. In this palace there are still goods, such as two trains named Paksi Naga Liman and Jempana which are still well maintained and stored in the museum. The shape is burak, the animal that was driven by the Prophet Muhammad when he was Isra Mi\'raj. Not far from the train, there is the Jinem ward, or the Hall to receive guests, the coronation of the sultan and the blessing of an event like the Prophet\'s Birthday. And in the middle of the palace there is a complex of buildings called Siti Hinggil. The interesting thing about the Palace in Cirebon is the existence of original Chinese porcelain plates which decorate the walls of all the palaces in Cirebon. Not only in the palace, ceramic plates were scattered in almost all historic sites in Cirebon. And no less important than the Palace in Cirebon is that the palace always faces north. And in the yard there is a tiger statue as a symbol of King Siliwangi. In front of the palace there is always a square for the people to gather and the market as the center of the economy, to the east of the palace there is always a mosque.</string>
    <string name="deskripsi_mesjid_agung_sang_cipta">That said, this mosque is the oldest mosque in Cirebon, which was built around 1480 AD or during Wali Songo spread Islam in Java. The name of the mosque is taken from the word \"sang\" which means majesty, \"copyright\" which means built, and \"taste\" which means used. According to tradition, the construction of this mosque was reportedly involved around five hundred people brought in from Majapahit, Demak, and Cirebon itself. In its construction, Sunan Gunung Jati appointed Sunan Kalijaga as its architect. In addition, Sunan Gunung Jati also brought Raden Sepat, the Majapahit architect who was a prisoner of the Demak-Majapahit war, to help Sunan Kalijaga design the mosque building. That said, this mosque had a memolo or roof peak. However, when the call to prayer (seven) of the Fajr prayer was held to expel the Aji Menjangan Wulung, the dome moved to the Banten Grand Mosque which still has two domes. Because of this story, until now every Friday prayer at the Great Mosque of Sang Cipta Rasa is held by Azan Pitu. Namely, the call to prayer is carried out simultaneously by seven people in all white uniforms.</string>
    <string name="deskripsi_makam_sunan_gunung_jati">Sunan Gunung Jati was born in 1450 AD, but there are also those who say that he was born in 1448 AD. Entering adulthood, around 1470, he married the younger brother of the then Regent of Banten, Nyai Kawunganten. From this marriage was born Ratu Wulung Ayu and Maulana Hasanuddin. It was Maulana Hasanuddin who later became the first King of Banten. Sheikh Syarif Hidayatullah passed away to Rahmatullah on the 26th of Rayagung in 891 Hijri or to coincide with the year 1568 AD. The Javanese date is 11 Krisnapaksa month of Badramasa in 1491 Saka. Died at the age of 120 years. With such a long age, his son and grandson did not have the opportunity to lead Cirebon, because they died first. His leadership continued by his great-grandson who led the Sultanate of Cirebon after the death of Syarif Hidayatullah. Sheikh Syarif Hidayatullah came to be known as Sunan Gunung Jati because it was buried in Bukit Gunung Jati</string>
    <string name="deskripsi_taman_sari">This is the Kaputren Park, a playground for the sons and daughters of the empire. The Kaputren Park after the Nurgiri Saptarengga Kaputren Park turned into a pesarean or tomb that we know as the tomb of Sunan Gunung Jati. After the park captain Nurgiri Saptrengga was used for funerals the Cirebon sultanate practically had no playground. So look for a place on the map of the Netherlands in 1648 said water castel because we are in the middle of the lake. The name of the lake is the teak ampara. Segara is a river like a lake, teak amparet because of its surrounding teak amparet. Sunyaragi Cave is in the middle of the lake. First, for security, not all people can enter, meaning people even if they use rafts or getekan (Cirebon language). Secondly, the function of the water is for air conditioning because all of the space is drained by water from the lake. Its main function is that water is used for ablution when there are people doing I\'tikaf or panyepi ing sport. We use the term panyepi ing raga so the name of the sunyaragi cave which originally was the panyepi ing raga kaputren park from panyepi ing raga was later changed to sunyaragi. Sunya from the word quiet yeast is body. Panyepi ing raga means singing away from the bustling world. We use the local wisdom of panyepi ing raga because if the word ascetic belongs to our brothers and sisters Hindus.</string>
    <string name="deskripsi_cirebon_waterland">Taman Ade Irma Suryani was originally named Taman Taman Traffic Garden Cirebon. Since 1966 it was changed to Taman Ade Irma Suryani Nasution. This park is the only recreational park and playground in the city of Cirebon. Ade Irma Suryani Park is located adjacent to the port of Cirebon with a location on the seafront of the north coast of Cirebon which has an area of + 2.5 Ha. This amusement park is the only family entertainment and recreation place near the coast of the city of Cirebon that provides children\'s play facilities, zoos, marine / beach tourism and other supporting facilities, a routine event on Sundays in the form of entertainment music events supported by artists famous artists including events in the form of a race for school children before the holidays.</string>
    <string name="deskripsi_pantai_kejawan">Cirebon Kejawan Beach is one of the beaches in the Cirebon region, West Java, Indonesia. Cirebon Kejawan Beach is a beach tourism site, a place for fish management (TPI Kejawan) and a therapeutic tour. Located on Jl.Yos Sudarso, Cirebon City, it is located close to the Port of Cirebon and Ade Irma Traffic Garden Cirebon. The entry fee is only one thousand rupiah, for vehicle users, both private cars and motorbikes, while for pedestrians there is no entrance fee. In Kejawan Beach besides we can enjoy the sunrise with a good position, which is right in the middle of the beach. There, we can also tour around the beach by using a motorboat owned by fishermen, with a fairly cheap tariff that costs only five thousand Rupiah per person, which can even be bargained up to three thousand rupiah. In addition, there are also many rubber boats for rent at rates ranging from five thousand Rupiah to ten thousand Rupiah per boat every hour, during the Eid holiday / if you\'re lucky we can see fishing boats / tugs because it is located close to the Port of Cirebon and we can take pictures on the boat and see fishermen carrying sea produce. The condition of the gently sloping and shallow coastline becomes its own attraction for visitors, especially children. Because they can play water to the middle of the beach. Even so, visitors are still required to always be careful. If we are hungry on the beach we can eat seafood with a view towards the sea.</string>
    <string name="tiket_keraton_kanoman">Entrance\t\tRp.10.000</string>
    <string name="operasional_keraton_kanoman">Monday – Sunday (Everyday) \nPukul 09.00 – 17.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_mesjid_agung_sang_cipta">Monday – Sunday (Everyday) 24 Hou</string>
    <string name="tiket_makam_sunan_gunung_jati">Pedestrian\tRp.1.000 \nCar\t\tRp.10.000</string>
    <string name="operasional_makam_sunan_gunung_jati">Monday – Sunday (Everyday) 24 Hour</string>
    <string name="tiket_taman_sari">Entrance\tRp.10.000 \nAttraction\t\tRp.10.000 – Rp.20.000</string>
    <string name="operasional_taman_sari">"Monday – Friday\t\t 08.00 – 17.00 WIB \n\nSaturday – Sunday\t 08.00 – 18.00 WIB "</string>
    <string name="tiket_cirebon_waterland">"Monday – Friday\t\t\tRp.50.000 \nSaturday – Sunday (Holiday)\tRp.65.000 \nAttraction\t\tRp.10.000 – Rp.15.000 "</string>
    <string name="operasional_cirebon_waterland">Monday – Sunday\t 07.00 – 21.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="tiket_pantai_kejawan">"Entrance\t\tRp.1000 \nMotorcycle Parking\tRp.2000 \nCar Parking\tRp.5000 "</string>
    <string name="operasional_pantai_kejawan">Monday – Sunday (Everyday)\t \n06.00 – 18.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="navigasi">Find Location</string>
    <string name="transportasi">Transportation</string>
    <string name="transportasi_populer">Popular Transportation</string>
    <string name="operasional_bubur_sop">Monday – Sunday\t \n09.00 – 17.30 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_docang">Monday – Sunday\t\n06.00 – 11.00 \n17.00 – 21.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_empal_gentong">Monday – Sunday\t\n07.00 – 21.30 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_nasi_lengko">Monday – Sunday\t\n08.00 – 22.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_tahu_gejrot">Monday – Sunday\t\n09.00 – 17.30 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_nasi_jamblang">"Monday – Sunday\t\n07.00 – 21.00 WIB \n\nSaturday – Sunday\t\n07.00 – 19.00 WIB "</string>
    <string name="operasional_mie_koclok">Monday – Sunday\t\n15.30 – 22.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_kue_tapel">Monday – Sunday\t06.00 – 15.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_sate_kalong">Monday – Sunday\t19.00 – 23.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_gado_gado">"Saturday – Thursday\t\t\n06.00 – 14.30 WIB \n\nFriday\t\t\t\nClose "</string>
    <string name="kuliner">Culinary</string>
    <string name="kuliner_populer">Popular Culinary</string>
    <string name="operasional_batik_trusmi">"Monday – Thursday\t\n08.30 – 19.00 WIB \n\nFriday – Saturday\t\t\n8.30 – 19.30 WIB "</string>
    <string name="operasional_salma_trusmi">"Weekday\t\t\n07.30 – 19.30 WIB \n\nWeekend\t\n07.30 – 20.00 WIB "</string>
    <string name="operasional_batik_nofa">"Weekday\t\t\n07.30 – 19.30 WIB \n\nWeekend\t\n07.30 – 20.00 WIB "</string>
    <string name="operasional_eb_batik">Monday – Sunday\t\n08.00 – 18.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_batik_asofa">Everyday\t\nPukul 08.00 – 18.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_pangestru">Everyday\t\n08.00 – 17.30 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_daud">Everyday\t\n08.00 – 21.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_rahayu">Everyday\t\n08.00 – 17.30 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_sinta">Everyday\t\n07.00 – 20.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_sumber_jaya">Everyday\t\n07.30 – 21.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_kanoman">Everyday\t\n02.00 – 18.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_pgc">Everyday\t\n08.00 – 20.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_csb">Everyday\t\n10.00 – 22.00 WIB</string>
    <string name="operasional_grage">"Monday – Thursday\t\t\t\n09.30 – 21.30 WIB \n\nFriday - Sunday\t\n09.30 – 22.00 WIB "</string>
    <string name="operasional_grage_city">Everyday\t\t\n09.30 – 21.30 WIB</string>
    <string name="fasilitas_masjid">Mosque</string>
    <string name="fasilitas_hotel">Hotel</string>
    <string name="fasilitas_rs">Hospital</string>
    <string name="fasilitas_lainnya">More</string>
    <string name="fasilitas_restoran">Restaurant</string>
    <string name="fasilitas_nongkrong">Hangout</string>
    <string name="fasilitas_spbu">Gas</string>
    <string name="fasilitas_bengkel">Garage</string>
    <string name="fasilitas">Public Space</string>
    <string name="hotel_populer">Popular Hotel</string>
    <string name="resto_populer">Popular Restaurant</string>
    <string name="nongkrong_populer">Hangout Popular Places</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard" translatable="false">History</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Profile</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="splashscreen_mulai">Lets Start !</string>
    <string name="splashscreen_akun">Already Have an Account?</string>
    <string name="splashscreen_login">Log In</string>
    <string name="splashscreen_daftar">Sign Up</string>
    <string name="login_akun">Don\'t Have an Account?</string>
    <string name="login_daftar">Sign In Here</string>
    <string name="register_nama">Name</string>
    <string name="register_telp">Phone Number</string>
    <string name="password">Password</string>
    <string name="registrasi_password">Confirm Password</string>
    <string name="logout">Log Out</string>
    <string name="semua">All Categories</string>
    <string name="pencarian">Search</string>
    <string name="belanja_populer">Popular Shoping Place</string>

</resources>